Sentences that are not explicitely marked as by Ulf or Jomon, are spoken by Ulf.

Discussion on the topic of Phase 3 - Building Trainings. (We used to say Module selection and Format selection, but it's now combined into "Building Trainings"). Now I think the Phase 3 Task 1 is Building Trainings, and Task 2 is Scheduling/defining the timeline for training on a high level. 

So our modules are actually defined already in the Learning Objectives task. So we have one module for each competency level and also further we can separate between Method and Tool if possible or applicable. For example, if we have a competency with PMT breakdown, then we have 2 modules for each of that competency level, one for method and one for tool.  

So these are our modules, so it's not about actually defining modules, it's about building trainings using these modules. From my experience, there are two different ways how you can build up trainings. 

The first one is the "competency level" based Training view. - So you say we have a training for the "competency 1 Level 2 for the Tool", and the following roles will participate in there. Similarly should we have a training for competency 1 Level 2 for the Method, and the following roles will participate in there.
And also a training for Competency 2 level 4 method, etc.. (Here, Ulf has shown me a figure where he has drawn boxes for each training one below the other, and on the left side of these boxes, the roles are listed that are in need of those trainings. (the roles that we have already identified in Learning Objectives task for each competency level that needs training). Remind me to share with you the image of the demo view Ulf has created).

The Second view is where we would have Roles Clustered, because it's not role cluster (not to be confused with the 14 standard role clusters we have in our app), but clustered roles - Trainings view. For example, for the role "engineer", you can call it "Systems Engineering for engineers" and inside the "Systems Engineering for engineers", you show all competencies and their levels and their Method - Tool (MT) separations within this "Systems Engineering for engineers" section that's for the Engineer role cluster. For example, "Competency 1 for "Engineers" or Competency 1 for "Leaders" (or Managers), etc.. However, the training module - Competency 1 for "Leaders" is part of the Strategy SE for Managers (when the strategy "SE for Managers" is selected). Or then there can be competencies for Interfacing Partners.
What we might need to do beforehand is to define which roles are part of Engineering, which roles are part of Leaders, which roles are part of Interfacing Partners, etc. - The Clustered Roles. We would say for example like requirements engineers, managers - they are all engineering responsible and then clustering based on that. (Jomon thinking to myself: are managers part of engineering responsible? maybe Ulf said it wrong). 
 
Jomon: So we have clustering based on the role (using the role names and their descriptions) and also based on the selected strategy as well. So we have 2 clusterings, correct? 

Ulf: Correct. So first of all, We need to ask the user the question of How do you want to build up your trainings? Do you want to have a Competency based training where several roles can participate? Or do you want to have role based trainings which then focus on different competencies and levels. 

So the question is How do we structure the modules? Do we structure it according to the competency level?, Or do we structure it at roles level and their associated competencies. This is what I've seen in practice - The two different ways of how it is done and as a good way to structure the training.

Jomon: so we have these two different types of variations. So do we ask the user beforehand which version or What kind of training they would prefer?
Ulf: correct and we explain a little bit the implication of choosing the variation, that we either "focus on the competency and its roles and bring all roles together", or "we focus on the roles and their specific tasks and therefore We will make a clustering. I'm not sure if we will have like "requirements Engineering" competency for requirements engineer roles and "requirements engineering" competency for system architect roles. So I would say it's requirements engineering for engineer roles. And part of that is also, the method and the tool topic inside it if they have this MT breakdown. (Jomon thinking to myself - so how do we distinguish or select the competencies between the clustered roles).

Jomon: Every competency we have does not have this method, tool breakdowns. So we do this further module breakdown into different tool and method modules only for the competencies that have this breakdown. 

Ulf: correct. for the other competencies without this breakdown, We will not have that further module breakdown then. But this is also something I realize, especially when we think about a low maturity company, they will probably have no Tools used in the company. Correct. So we maybe need the possibility to deselect competencies as well. so maybe it would be like just a checkbox where I can deselect the identified modules (or that competency entirely).

Jomon: So this deselection ability of identified competency levels - are we implementing this feature in the Learning Objectives results page? And have a checkbox or a button beside each competency level that we have identified in the Learning Objectives results page? 

Ulf: yes, that would be in the Learning Objectives results page that you can deselect. it's just like a little button where you can deselect the learning objectives. 

Ulf then navigates to the app dashboard page. Here he sees the text shown for Phase 3 as "Macro Planning - Select learning modules and qualification formats".Ulf says we need to rename the description so that it does not say "select learning modules".  Ulf says that I can start thinking about. Ulf says: I would say we have our modules - like our small pieces with learning objectives, and each learning objectives leads to one module. How we then build up from the modules the training is what should be done here and written as description. 

Ulf says: So maybe it's Define Training modules, instead of "Select learning modules". The "qualification formats" part is correct and needed in the Micro Planning phase 3.

Ulf: then we have also think about the micro planning itself. Besides the Define Training modules and selecting formats, defining the timeline itself would be actually part of macro planning. so saying like, when shall the concept be developed, When shall the development of the concept start, When should shall the concept definition end, When shall the first training be performed, and When shall the last training be performed. So we need to have like an overview of these timeline topics. 

Jomon: Understood. So it's about how we schedule the different trainings.
Ulf: Correct. 

Ulf: Well, I mean, maybe we need to have this kind of timeline in 2 aspects, because on a micro planning phase, we would say, this is In 25 and 26, and we want 12 trainings. In Q1 of 2026, We will define the concept. This is like the macro planning. and in the next Phase 4: micro planning, it's again then about We need to define when each of the training will actually be performed. But this kind of planning, again as I think about it, it's not part of the concept. So we keep this kind of planning - just the big picture for macro planning in Phase 3. 

Ulf: so what's within the Phase 3 macro planning? What needs to be done here is that we define the trainings, we will select the format - maybe We provide the list of formats with their benefits and they can select by themselves. (But we also do format recommendations based on some input aspects). And then we define the timeline on a high level.


Jomon: I have a made some notes on this format recommendations that I can share with you as well. So we can go through this together. The file PHASE3_LF_CONCEPTUAL_DESIGN.md is what I showed Ulf. 

Then we talk about the Learning formats for the modules we show in the Building Trainings page. What are the 3 main factors that we want to consider for the learning formats? - So do we want high interaction? Maybe we could also build up recommendation based on the number of participants. So you say, how many people will have to be trained. for example, up to 100 participants, then it means in personal trainings - 10 in personal trainings (i didnt understand why Ulf said 10 in-personal trainings. maybe mistake when speaking from his side.), if it's to 1000s You should think about the e-learning format to cater to the larger amount of participants. (Read further below to see the finalized 3 main factors for learning format recommendation that we decided together).

Jomon: so here we are trying to come up with recommendation for the users - what can be the better suited learning format for each competency level. 
So the inputs that we use are the training group size from Phase 1, then we have the gap data in the phase 2, and the total number of users per competency level are in need of training. 
Jomon: Then we already have the learning objectives generated for it. And what we have are the 10 different learning formats that Sachin has defined and the other inputs associated with learning formats that Sachin has defined in his thesis. Sachin also has the "Competency - learning format matrix" or table defined. 
Jomon: So the main idea is to use this table as well. Does that make sense? 

Ulf: So I would say yes. but the only thing is, I'm not a 100% sure how valid these value mappings are between the competencies and learning formats. But let's use it for it. Also, this table says nothing about the levels you can achieve with it, and it says how well it is suited to address this competency. 
And another concern with the table that I just realized is that there are values like 5,6,7,.. when the "Mapping scale" legend says values to be 0,2,4. So this table is not correct. However, just from the looking at the table overall, I would say that I would come to similar conclusions from how good it is to achieve these certain aspects (the learning formats for each competencies). Or I was thinking, if it would make more sense not to use like relevant, irrelevant and so on, But instead, which competency level so like our 1,2,4 and 6 can be achieved with each of those learning formats for each of the competencies. (Also the competency names are maybe different in this table than what we have defined in our app). 

Jomon: So these values in this table have to be evaluated and use this inference to derive competency level values that can be achieved for each competency for each of the Learning formats by me. 

Ulf: yes, also because then we will also come to the point that things like Systems thinking, Lifecycle Consideration, ... (the 4 core competencies) are competencies that you cannot do that with learning formats. It's something which comes by experience. So one thing is that you know that that is, but a higher level (even Understanding level) is somehow usually hard to achieve. So I would use this kind of the same table matrix, but instead of having numbers from 0 to 7 as Sachin has defined it, I would use our numbers ofour competency levels. (Jomon thinking to myself: mainly values as 0,1,2,4 and not a lot of 6's or very few 6's).

Ulf: I'm pretty sure that there's a correlation between the relevance that is mentioned here in Sachin's table and the competency levels that can be achieved. Probably it's quite similar. However, I would adapt this in that way, and then use it. 

Jomon: Um yeah, so this is the "Competency - learning format matrix" that we can use from Sachin apart from the formats and the advantages disadvantages, and other things Sachin has defined in his thesis. He also has defined a "Strategy - Learning format" (Strategy/Archetype) mapping. But if I recall correctly in the last meeting we discusse, the selected strategy does not affect the learning format recommendations.

Ulf: That's a good point. I was thinking the same way earlier, so of course, there is a correlation somehow between the strategy and learning formats. So, for example, if you say you want the training with Strategy as "common basic understanding", the suggestion would be not to use E-learning format. So we need to create an overview of the learning formats - a mapping table or matrix between these 10 learning formats And the Archetypes. And we say for mapping values as 3 possbilities: "highly recommended", "partly recommended", and "not consistent" with the strategies. And again, this information is actually already present in Sachin's work but it's not well defined or well picked I would say. 

Once we have this table (Archetype - Learning Format matrix) created, we can use it to inform the user that -> You have the following competency selected. So on the back end, a calculation will happen where we will check if the user's selected format is recommended, And if there is inconsistency, then, we will just inform the users saying that the selected format has an inconsistency. Maybe we also enter the rationale to why there's this inconsistency as a feedback.
That would be great because then we still have the consideration of the strategy for Learning formats, And we can generate the feedback if there's inconsistency, say that these are the right things to use and to do here. 

Jomon: That makes sense. So the strategy - learning format mapping is also something we should consider. 

Jomon: (continuing the explanation of "PROCESSING STEPS" from the PHASE3_LF_CONCEPTUAL_DESIGN.md). Then, what we do is that for each competency level, We find the number of users and the gap And then we also analyze the distribution patterns described in DISTRIBUTION_SCENARIO_ANALYSIS.md. 

Jomon: So after this, I explained the "STEP 3: FILTER FORMATS BY LEVEL (E-Learning Rule)". If it is an Applying level that we want to achieve, then we are thinking of excluding the computer-based.

Ulf:Correct, this is actually the same as what we have discussed just before about Sachin's table or matrix. so if you build up the Matrix in the same way,  like for example, the competency "System thinking", and you need to get on level 4 with system thinking, you will see then that you can get level 4 with seminar, coaching, mentoring, but not with the "conference" or "computer-based learnings". So Similarly you have to think of values in "Competency - learning format matrix" that we discussed in this meeting just before. Perfect. 

Jomon: So perfecting this "Competency - learning format" matrix is something what we had to do. So the 2 matrices that we have to create are "Competency - learning format" matrix and "Strategy - learning format" matrix.  

Ulf: Correct. 

Jomon: After this, then comes the different ranking of which format would be better (STEP 4: SCORE AND RANK FORMATS). So for each format, and for each level, there are different input aspects we consider. one of them is the User count appropriateness - How many people need that level.

Ulf: The one question that I have and Maybe you have to do some research on that, but my suggestion would be that I'm not sure if we will do or Choose many different formats for different trainings. (Jomon thinking to myself: Maybe Ulf's talking about the different training modules having different learning formats).
Ulf: But of course it could make sense to be having many different formats. For example, if we have something like a group of 2000 people who need to be trained, and another group of 8 people in need of training, (Jomon thinking: maybe Ulf's talking about the DISTRIBUTION_SCENARIO_ANALYSIS patterns.), then Of course, it makes sense to differentiate that and choose different formats. So yeah, keep the SCORE AND RANK FORMATS for each competency level.

Ulf: What all do we have as input factors in the "STEP 4: SCORE AND RANK FORMATS"? 
Jomon: We have 1. user count appropriateness, 2. the distribution pattern -> An example scenario from the DISTRIBUTION_SCENARIO_ANALYSIS, where when we have two different groups - where one group are all experts and the other group are biginners, then we are suggesting different formats for the same competency level. 3. We have the competency - learning format matrix from Sachin that needs to be reworked to use appropriate level values as the mappings. 4. We have the strategy - learning format matrix that we will create based on Sachin's work.

Ulf: To be honest, Jomon, I'm not sure if we really need to make this calculation. I think we try to over-complicate the solution at some point. That was something I realized just last time. I think it's actually good enough to give an overview and presenting it to the user like - these are the training information we have for you. And we can do the "STEP 4: SCORE AND RANK FORMATS" to give an overview when the user selects a learning format, for example, as seminar, you get information or feedback for each learning objective (that is, a recommendation for each competency and each level and further MT breakdown modules). Here, Ulf thinks that: Hey, this would be then a lot of Information to get processed by the user when he sees this page. So let me think here. So, We only focus on the gaps (the learning objectives have this data shown as "Training Requirements Identified" in the app frontend.). So it could be that if the gaps are low, then you don't have much to click and view. If your gaps are high, you have lots to click and view but it's fine. 

So I would say before we get into this whole thing, I would say that the first step is that we ask the user and define if we want competency based clusters or role base clusters. (This is the same thing we dicussed in the beginning of meeting) (Also for low maturity company, we would only have competency based view and no need to ask user for what they prefer because there are no roles defined in the company. Just like how to do it in the Learning Objectives page and show only the "Organizational View").

And then we show the whole Training view. For example, the competency "requirements management" for Engineers (role cluster) is the first thing that's created where we will analyze what kind of format is going to be used. And then we provide the information If you click on seminar, you will see that this format is suitable/not suitable because of these reasons: 
The input factor 1: User count appropriateness or the number of participants -> for example, if the number of participants who will get engineering training are below 100 So or below 200, so we make it then green colored to show that this is a good format and say it's fine.
The input factor 2: To be the achieved competency level appropriateness using the "Competency - learning format" matrix.
The input factor 3: Strategy - learning format consistency.

Essentially, we are not making the calculations and preselecting the formats, but instead we let the user select their desired format and then we show info like whether it's a suitable learning format based on the 3 input factors described above and marking each of the status of those 3 factors like green, yellow, red, etc..
(Jomon thinking to myself: So basically, we are not doing the ranking and scoring of formats, but instead we are showing the suitability of the selected format based on the 3 input factors. Then does the DISTRIBUTION_SCENARIO_ANALYSIS patterns come into picture here? Need to think about it.)

And then the remaining we also show when you click on the format, what the benefits and disadvantages (I think Sachin's posters for the formats), and then we can finally say all right it is perfect. For example - if you click on something like Learn more about the format button, then you should show the Sachin's poster. And then the user can select it by themselves. So there is NO RECOMMENDATION of learning format, but instead we provide the information to the user when they select format by themselves.  it's just like using the information to show which one can should be selected and giving the user feedback on their selection.

Jomon: So when we talk about the input factor: User count, there's a conflict between 2 input sources. So we have the "target group size for training" that we have as an input from the Phase 1 as (<20, 20-100, 100-500, 500-1500, >1500). So that's an input number that we already have. Then we also the user count from the actual app users who have completed their compet assessments and have gaps and need training -> The data that we used to calculate the learning objectives. So these are a different set of user counts. So which of these inputs will we use? 
The underlying problem here is that if we say the target group size for training in Phase 1 is 100-500, then every employee in the company needs to use our app and do the competency assessment to get the real gap data to use for training planning. But in reality, max 10 to 20 users will use the app and do the competency assessment. So the real user count for training planning will be very low compared to the target group size for training. So which of these two user counts will we use for learning format recommendation?

Ulf: Correct, we can then match the numbers as a statistic value, and you factor with everything from say, 10 app users to scale and count up to 200 for example. So we can do some kind of scaling factor to match the numbers that are sensible with the target group size for training and the competency assessment data of app users. Ulf says that we try to scale it more towards the higher numbers to use as data.

Ulf: When we think about the gap calculation when factoring in the scaling up of user counts, for example from 10 app users gap data to the 200 as training size, lets say we have 200 persons who need to be trained. But 150 have already level 2, so there is only 50 that need to be trained to level 2. This makes sense. So of course, you can use a different style when it's if the other way around say if it's 2000. So, scaling up of user counts is something we need to do sensibly and logically. 


So basically, only if you click on a training format below, then there's like these 3 factors/parameters which are green or red to identify if the format matches based on the strategy, number of participants, and the competency level.


Ulf: I actually wanted to share with you this file "SE Qualification Program - Input for identifying training service providers.pdf". This document is almost what we want to create as a final output from our app and to be exported as a document. If we can create something similar, and it does not have to be exactly the same, but to identify would be our output. Our app will provide definitely more information than what's in this example pdf document, but It's just like double-checking if we would come to similar things at the very end. Because that's actually our goal. (Add this requirement to the backlog to guide and validate our app's design and output).

Ulf: one further thing that just came in my mind when I was navigating through the app, do we have the questioning about whether there are existing trainings in the company? 

Jomon: No, we currently don't have this feature implemented.

Ulf: That's something we should do. Just integrate So after the Get analysis, we should ask - for which of these competencies do the training exists already in the company And then the user can just deselect the competencies so that they are not further considered. For example, saying it like - "Please check if there are certain trainings that already exist in the organization for the listed competencies so that those should not be considered, or there are certain trainings you want to exclude from the further development, and then you can deselect the things and then continue."  And we would be deselecting the individual competencies as a whole including the competency levels inside them. And we can implement this feature in the Learning Objectives dashboard page wehre we show the Assessment Monitoring, etc. So we implement this feature before generating the learning objectives and also take this into consideration when generating the learning objectives to remove all Learning objectives for competencies that have existing trainings in the company.


Jomon: I showed Ulf the "3.3 Level-Based Format Restrictions (HARD CONSTRAINT)" table in the PHASE3_LF_CONCEPTUAL_DESIGN file. Then Ulf thinks that I've already created something similar. I said that this table shows info about which Format would be suitable for each of the levels. But this does not take into account which competency those levels belong to. 

Ulf: But to be honest, I'm pretty sure this is good. I bet you can use it. I would request you to double-check it. and I'm pretty sure that the "Competency - Learning format" matrix will almost look similar like to this table. 

Jomon: Okay. So this table is mainly for the e-learning constraint. But yes, definitely, I will have to double-check and create the "Competency - Learning format" matrix using the values in this table as a reference. So, I need to create the "Competency - Learning format" matrix using this table as a reference and Sachin's work as a reference. 

Ulf: And the last thing again, that I've said already previously, is that I dont want you to automate and make decisions for everything. We just have to give a good overview of options and provide the possibility to select to the user. And always give feedback to the user saying like if you select this then these things can happen. Just like what we have discussed. Yeah, saying like - it is a good choice to select this and the reason is because it's a good idea because of this and this factors, but not a good idea because of this another factor, etc..

Ulf: The last thing is about the timeline, which is also part of the macro planning. Maybe you can, you can think about it or find reference research book or papers that describe what are the typical timeline phases. So you can have a detailed concept phase, the pilot phase, and the run phase. Maybe these 3 possible things from my suggestion, and you enter this information in here in the Macro planning page. There is no information about when to start the concept, when to end, when the first pilot should start, etc. in the "SE Qualification Program - Input for identifying training service providers.pdf" file I shared with you. But this information is necessary to be implemented in the Phase 3 macro planning. 


Ulf: Then in phase 4, we will make it quite simple. We will just Create for each training an AVIVA template. 

Ulf: I need to share with you the AVIVA template examples. In the AVIVA template where we have another row for learning objectives. And the rest is like it's open And needs to be done. But I would not do the rest in our app, but instead we will export this as an Excel file and then we can edit or adapt the values in Excel file. 

Jomon: I then briefly presented to Ulf the "Export to excel" feature implemented in the Learning Objectives results page for his validation.

Ulf: I would say that it's implemented fine here in this Learning Objectives results page. So in the Phase 3, we would also need an Export to excel feature towards the end of Phase 3 that contains all the info that's already present in the Exported file in Learning Objectives results page, and additionally what I would also need additionally is the information about How many people is going to be trained, the selected learning format. So, all the further information that we have talked today, I would also integrate this all here. So finally at the very end, An exported excel sheet with overview of all the information. 

Jomon: So once the phase 3 ends, and we have more data like the number of people going to be trained, and the learning format, and the timeline data that we can integrate into one Excel sheet. 

Ulf: So I have one more thought that just came up to discuss. Let me share my screen and show the "SE Qualification Program - Input for identifying training service providers.pdf" file again and walk you through it.
Ulf: What's interesting for us is in the page 8 of this pdf that shows "Personnel subject to training" and has an Overview data of Number of persons for training modules. The training modules listed in this document are RqE1, RqE2, RqE3, SyA1, SyA2, SyA3, SyA4. In the overview shown in page 8, they have defined how many people have to be take part for the training module Requirements Engineering level 1 (RqE1), Requirements Engineering level 2 (RqE2), etc.. And they calculate or describe here about how many people have to participate at each of these training modules. They say here that 448 Engineers need RqE1, 94 need RqE2, 41 need RqE3, etc.. So this is something very similar to what we have to do in our Phase 3 and what we have discussed in this meeting.  

Ulf: Maybe you can create an overview similar to this in the Phase 3's Export to excel functionality of finalized training modules with the user counts. This would be similar to what we've already done in Learning Objectives export to excel feature where it includes the roles needing training for each competency level. But now we need to have the number of people needing training for each training module. So this is something we need to do additionally.

Ulf: In this Phase 3 page, we need to display this additional information as well - suppose only 10 users participate at the competency assessment by using our app, We need to give the user the information that for further consideration of the training, we have used this limited competency assessment data as an input and we have scaled it up to the numbers you have provided before in Phase 1 as an input for the Target group size for training. We should do this so that the user is aware that these are Estimations of user counts that we've scaled up to match the target group size input provided. 

Ulf: Using these estimated higher user counts would be a better input factor to the Learning format decisions rather than just using only the limited number of users who have completed the competency assessment. Then we can better create a similar overview of how many people would get trained in these competencies/modules as shown in the pdf document. 


---

Conversation about the final output document that we want to create from our app (not discussing about Phase 3 here).

Ulf: For the purpose of explaining to you what we want to create as a final output from our app that we can then export as a document, let me walk you through this "SE Qualification Program - Input for identifying training service providers.pdf" document again. Our app's final output should be similar to this document and we can use LLM to generate something similar. We generate it as the last step of our app where we can call it as "Generate a Request for Proposal", where we would say - based on all the information we've got through all the Phases in the app, you get to create this Request for Proposal document (.docx filetype).  

Ulf: So let's walkthrough the sections of this pdf file. what we have first is the Context, and Core Concept sections. The Context section is more generalized to what Systems Engineering is about. When we talk about the Core Concept section, it is something very organisation specific that's tailored to their context. So I would say that we can maybe generate something similar to this Core Concept using GenAI LLM based. In the Core Concept section, we need the "The core personnel to be trained include:" part with the list of all roles that we identify for training and other parts that can be created using LLM. 
Then, we will need this Service Description page - with the General requirements. In the line "Alignment with ZEISS regarding training contents and modalities" - Ulf said that this note here would be shown only for high maturity organisations as we are asking the org to input their Processes, methods, and tools data that exist in their org only for high maturity pathway in our app.
Then, we will need this "Service Description Requirements/ Constraints" page as well. ... The first point - "Trainer shall be proficient in systems engineering,.." is something standard and can be reused without needing LLM customization of this info part. The second point - "For some training modules the trainer shall be able to delve into ZEISS MED processes." would be also something we could generate because we hopefully get processes data from PMT collection in the app. The third point - "Trainer shall be willing to travel to locations" - this can be generated as generic once we have the learning format info. If it's e-learning format, then we can say that travel is not needed. If it's seminar format, then we can say that travel is needed. So this part can be generated based on the selected learning format. The 4th point - "Training material shall be provided in English" - this can be reused and is standard info. And the rest of the points that are in this page can be generated as well based on the info we have in the app for that org.
Then, we will need this "Service Description Personnel subject to training" page as we discussed earlier in this meeting for Phase 3. This page contains the overview of the roles, the number of persons for training modules, etc.  
Then we need the rest of the pages in this document as well. The Key Competencies, The overview of each of the Training modules with their Goals and Contents.

Ulf: So this file is something that's actually what we're going to create. This reference pdf that we read through is an actual file someone has defined. And our app will help to define or create this document. 

Ulf: At the end of Phase 3 we can have another step that asks user to define or input the requirements for the training - because then we have the selected learning formats. So we would be able to make inferences like if the format is seminar, then the trainers need to be experts, So they're like general things that you write in this output document. And we can use LLM to support and create these general things in the final document that we export from the app.

(End of conversation about the final output document of the app.)
