Jomon: We get to phase 3. I've explained to Ulf here about the role-clustered training programs (SE for Engineers, SE for Managers, SE for Interfacing Partners) and how the roles are assigned to these 3 training programs based on their competency gaps and that there is also an inside clustering of modules into common base and role-specific pathways in SE for Engineers program.

Ulf: This is good. I need you to make sure that you explain all these things in your conceptual framework chapter in your thesis. Because for me, the conceptual aspect is more important than the implementation aspect.

Jomon: After the learning formats for every modules have been selected, then we would have the timeline estimation task.

Ulf: So in the timeline estimation/planning, does these timelines consider the modules?

Jomon: No, this timeline plan currently does not take into account for each module, but instead on a high level we are defining the timeline as something like this is where the concept development starts for all the modules, etc.. 

Ulf: So, maybe this is like, Let's say not a must have to requirement, but a nice to have requirement - that we would have also a separation in timeline of these different modules for different trainings.

Jomon: That makes sense. I'll add this requirement to the BACKLOG.md and work on it.

Jomon: we can do an Excel export once the Phase 3 tasks are done. And I explained to Ulf the exported Excel file.

Ulf: In this exported excel file, I like this kind of overview provided at top. What would be nice would be to have also some more detailed information included in these overview items (Training View, Selected Strategies, Target Group Size, Total Training Modules, Format Distribution). For example, adding info like "Target Group Size" was defined in Phase 1, "Selected Strategies" from Phase 1, "Training View", "Total Training Modules", "Format Distribution" all from Phase 3. Also for the Selected Strategies, explain a bit more about the strategy selected as a short summary. For example, the strategy "Continuous Support" - add it's description and notes to describe about the strategy as well. I think this information about strategies is already present in the Strategy profile cards defined in Phase 1 for all 7 strategies. So similarly provide a short description for the other overview items as well.

Ulf: one last question about the exported excel file is, does it also inlcude the timeline planning? 

Jomon: Yes, at the end of it we have the timeline planning included as well.

Ulf: Okay, maybe it would be nice to also add the detailed timeline planning to the Training Modules by having a new column after the "Est. Participants" column to include timeline planning information. This would make the timeline planning detailed and includes the consideration of all training modules. It would just be the mapping of these timelines here to the modules. So we would have the Implementation Timeline overview below as it is shown currently and then the more detailed view incorporated into the modules. These can also be estimated. 


Jomon: I've then showed Ulf the Phase 4 tasks. Currently we list all training modules defined in Phase 3 here and does not allow any selection of modules for generating the AVIVA or RFP document.

Ulf: Yeah, we need the possibility to allow the user to choose the modules they want in AVIVA or RFP so that if the user does not want to create the exports for all modules, they can have it as they want it to be. So write short sentence in this Task 1 of Phase 4 as something like - Now you have the possibility to select for which training concepts you want to create a detailed didactics using AVIVA. Also here you should explain shortly What AVIVA is to the user - it's a didactics concept for generating learning plans. And then like I said earlier, the user could select which all modules they want to have included in the AVIVA planning. It should be like checkboxes on each of the modules that allow selection-deselection of the currently listed modules. This way, the user can also then have the possibility to do a different selection of modules later and then generate a different AVIVA plan for a different set of modules.

Ulf: Also about the view shown currently regarding the training modules packages for SE for Engineers, SE for Managers, SE for Interfacing Partners - it would be nice to have an expand-collapse functionality here. So that at the start, we just see the high level view of the 3 training packages as collapsed cards and then the user can expand each package to see the modules included in it. This way, the user can have a better overview of the training packages without being overwhelmed by all the module details at once. So implement an expand-collapse functionality for these training packages view. Similarly if it's competency level based training structure, we can have the expand-collapse functionality for each of the 16 competencies showing the modules included in each competency when expanded. After this, also allow the selection of the higher level packages or competencies as checkboxes for selection-deselection of all modules within that package/competency. If they select the package/competency checkbox, all modules within that package/competency get selected. If they deselect the package/competency checkbox, all modules within that package/competency get deselected. This way, the user can easily select/deselect entire packages or competencies at once instead of selecting each module individually. This allows on a high level, that the user can have selection options on the main 3 packages.

Ulf: One simple change to be made is to have first of all have the overview of the 3 training packages - SE for engineers, SE for Managers, SE for Interfacing Partners, so the user understands that these are the 3 main training packages. Then below that, we can have the detailed view of the modules included in each package with the expand-collapse functionality as I explained earlier. This way, the user first sees the high level overview of the 3 packages and then can explore the module details within each package as they want. 

Jomon: Understood. That makes it easier for the reader to see the high level overview of the training packages first and they would appear collapsed initially also with the selection checkboxes for each package. Then when they expand a package, they can see the modules within it and select-deselect individual modules as well. 

So this Training modules overview is shown in Phase 4 Task 1 AVIVA page. Here the user can select the modules for which they want to generate the AVIVA didactics plan. Similarly in Phase 4 Task 2 RFP document export page, since we do not have this training modules overview shown currently, in the Export RFP Document div, we can ask user if they want to include only the modules selected in AVIVA page for export or to include all modules defined in Phase 3.

AVIVA Excel export discussion:

Ulf: One change you need to make is regarding the AVIVA module durations used. Currently it is Level 1 (2 hours), Level 2 (4 hours), Level 4 (8 hours), Level 6 (16 hours). I think these timings are a bit too high. So we can reduce them to Level 1 (1 hour), Level 2 (2 hours), Level 4 (4 hours), Level 6 (8 hours). So please change these timings in the AVIVA planning generation logic in the app.

Jomon: So we have to make it half of the currently defined duration for the levels. And also I have to find some academic research to support on this AVIVA planning durations. 

Ulf: It would be nice to do some research on that topic, at least underline that a little bit here on the AVIVA planning durations.

Ulf: I have some thoughts here in this exported excel file's "AVIVA Plans" sheet. It would be nice if we can bring 2 or more modules in 1 day and, it being like saying the first day is from 9 to 5, and at the end of 1st module, we start the next module, etc.. So that we can have multiple modules in 1 day. So that there's a need to create whole days and bring the modules together that they're gonna be in whole days. 

Jomon: I understood. But, there would not be parallel modules, right? For example, on 1 day for a fixed time, only one module is the training taking place?

Ulf: Correct. You have to also somehow synchronize the modules taking into consideration the learning formats chosen for each of the modules.

Ulf: When you take a look at the competency level based training structure, you can keep it as it is. If the role-cluster based training structure is chosen in Phase 3, for example, packages like SE for Engineers, .. maybe using LLM to say: I want now the possibility to have like the daily views, so that it brings the modules together and create such a schedule for training which brings it into a daily-like view, OR to have this separate view to synchronize to use the same learning formats (Webinar, WBT, ..) for everything at least per day. 

Ulf: because at the end, this Training Module planning should be somehow consistent. So that we have an overview of packages that are somehow consistent. 

Jomon: I understand. Yeah, so we have the modules that are within the packages, And for each modules, we have different formats, and we need to find a consistency and have the training days schedule taken into consideration. 

Ulf: One observation I have for the whole web application is that we need more explanations in the app everywhere to everything that we have did in each task in each Phase. Because the user would not be aware of what's happening in each task. For example, in Phase 4 Task 1 AVIVA Didactics - Explain what is happening here and  we describe why it is necessary and what shall be done and where is it based on?, ... So the user gets a better understanding and also regarding the RFP Task, we also need guidance explanations like saying - based on everything you have input and every information we have gathered together, we're going to create now the RFP document export for you that you can use, and what it is used for. And this counts for not just these tasks alone but also for all other tasks in all the Phases. Please double-check this for all the other Phases. - A good Guidance and Explanation for each step of the app - like why those steps are necessary and so on. 


Ulf: For the file exports that we do (the Phase 4 AVIVA excel, and the RFP Word document) that use GenAI to populate contents, there's also something we need to write at the very end of the document - like every GenAI topic, that this document or file is generated using GenAI and it could have mistakes. This document should be like a reference file or like a starting point and they might be changes necessary. 


Ulf: One requirement that I have to be implemented is that we have to reduce the number of training modules. My thought here is that if we cluster the modules for example, we already have the modules clustered into the 3 packages (SE for engineers, for Managers, for Interfacing Partners), then within these clusters let's define subclusters/submodules like - "SE for Engineers - Requirements Definiton". This would be 1 single training course for Requirements Definiton for roles in the SE for Engineers package. And this course would include every Method, Tool, and all identified competency level modules within the competency "Requirements Definiton". So maybe that is part of it is everything from method and tooling. 

Jomon: So the competency topic as a whole would be a one training cluster within the 3 main packages. 

Ulf: Yeah, it would be another training cluster. So we have the whole 3 packages like the package "SE for engineers", and within that package for engineers, we have we "Systems Thinking for engineers", we have "Requirements Definiton for engineers", etc.. and within these topics, we have then the sub modules (Tool, Method for each identfied levels Knowing (Level 1), Understanding (Level 2), Applying (Level 4), Mastering (Level 6)). 

Jomon: Okay. So this brings me to the question: so suppose we have 2 modules within a competency as Knowing level and Understanding level. Then, are these two fundamentally two different modules, or since they are clustered into the competency, Do we reduce the module count? 

Ulf: So yeah, I think we can reduce it, because we justify it by saying that - as they have to achieve level 2, we can actually skip level 1. Because level 1 is then automatically achieved by achieving level 2. But regarding the level 4, maybe it's necessary to have level 2 so that they have a little base to work on for achieving level 4. Creating such an overview of trainings by having the group within the group within the group. Focusing the grouping not on the level, but grouping on the competency module. 

Jomon: We need to include the detailed timeline into the Training Modules Overview of all the modules by adding a new column in the 4 excel sheet exports in the app (Phase 3 excel export, Phase 4 Task 1 AVIVA exports (Template, GenAI), Phase 4 RFP excel export).

Ulf: Yes, exactly. So that the user can see the detailed timeline planning for each module in the excel exports.

These changes to training module clustering and timeline planning in the excel exports are to be implemented in Phase 3 Excel export, Phase 4 Task 1 AVIVA exports (Template, GenAI), Phase 4 RFP excel export.
