All sentences that are not explicitly marked as by Jomon, are spoken by Ulf (my thesis advisor).
Discussion about the SE-QPT app implementation.

Jomon: About the "Existing training check" in learning Objectives dashboard page, currently we are just excluding the competency as a whole when they are selected and we don't differentiate between the levels within each competency. So for example, if a user has selected "Systems Thinking" competency as existing training, we are excluding all levels (1-4) of "Systems Thinking" competency from the learning objectives generation.

Ulf: We need level differentiation within competencies. For example, a company might be having an existing training program in the competency "Requirements definition" at Knowing level but no trainings for Understanding or Applying level. So maybe we can have this Existing traning check as a 2 step like process - first asking, do you have trainings in one of the following competency field? and then only for the selected ones, asking to which detail do you see these trainings? (levels 1,2,4).

Ulf: Phase 3 Task 1 - so it's 2 different possibilities to do the training programs. We need to redo the architecture/design spec for Phase 3 Tasks 1 and 2. For doing this, first can you make a mapping between the 7 training strategies (defined in Phase 1) and the 2 training program types (competency based and role based)? I think there is a correlation between these 2 kinds of training programs and the strategies to be used for training. I'm not sure if thats applicable for all of the 7 strategies but at least for some I would say we can say that it's recommended to use a competency based or to use the role based training program approach. For example, with the strategy "SE for managers", it makes sense to bring those Managerial roles together and have a role based training program for them. "Common basic understanding" strategy would also make sense to bring roles together for training. "Orientation in pilot project" is maybe both? So maybe just think about that how you could consider these 7 strategies in the context of these 2 training program types. 

Ulf: And however, it's not necessary yet to consider this aspect in your app implementation solution. I just want to get an idea if that makes sense in terms of how it should be proceeding. 

Jomon: So when we talk about role clustered based training, this is something that I wanted to discuss with you about how we are grouping the roles in the organization to these different 6 umbrella clusters or training groups, namely, Engineers, Managers, Executives, Support Staff, External Partners, and Operations.

Ulf: We only need 3 groups - Engineers, Managers, and Interfacing Partners. Executives can be part of Managers, Support Staff, External Partners, and Operations can be part of Interfacing Partners.

Jomon: So what I've done currently is to map the org roles in Phase 1 Task 2 to the 6 umbrella groups alongside the primary mapping to the 14 SE Role clusters.

Ulf: What I want to see is to build up these training group subclusters based on the based on the competency gaps data that we have. To do it in such a way where you see that these roles have very similar need for competencies. So thus we build a cluster with these roles, and then we name it accordingly. 

We could also think about it in this way: if a role need a level 4 or level 6 in one of the 5 technical competencies or in the 4 core competencies, then that role gets to be a part of SE for Engineers program. For example, whenever a role needs to apply (level 4) in competency "Systems Thinking" or in "Requirements Definition", then that role will get automatically moved into the SE for Engineers pathway.
If a role need a level 4 or higher only in the 3 Social/Personal competencies or the 4 Management Competencies, i.e., they only have the need for higher level trainings (level 4 or 6) in among these Social/Personal competencies or Management Competencies, and have no need for level 4 or above in any of the other competency groups, then they will get into the SE for Managers program. If they have a need for level 4 in any other competencies, then they will get into the SE for Engineers program instead. If a role needs only Knowing (Level 1) or Understanding (level 2), then that role will get into the SE for Interfacing Partners. 

So this would be the first possibility to cluster the training program into SE for Engineers, for Managers, and for Interfacing Partners. And then you could also define subclusters or a more detailed training version inside the primary training clustering in more detail really focusing on one certain role/role cluster. As an example scenario, let's say we have a role Requirements Engineer that primarily goes into the SE for Engineers program. Then we could have a more detailed training program inside the SE for Engineers program, which is called "SE for Requirements Engineers"  where it really focuses on the certain level they needs to achieve. So this would be a more detailed training program really focusing on the needs of Requirements Engineer.

The difference is, actually from a user perspective. So like someone who is consuming training is and in the competency level based view, I have a lot of options where I can select from. Where on the role-cluster Based, I have not so many options where I can select from. But within one cluster, it's already defined What I should know.

I'm not yet much sure. so I think it's fine to say we offer like big page on different trainings where you can choose from, or we say we have we have prepared packages for you based on your roles in the org. That's the difference. And I think I like to say that there are two different ways how you can handle it. And the only question that is now open is how do we build these packages? And we started with saying that we will build packages like SE for Engineers, for managers, and for interfacing Partners. But if we come to the topic of Engineers, that everyone who sees themselves as an engineer will need to know the competency on the highest level, even if you don't need it. And that's why I said that in this engineering aspect, maybe we will keep differentiating between all engineering roles we have. 

So I'm not sure how many it is, but it could be like 5 or 6 role clusters who are that I would consider as part of this engineering roles. We're also going to have SE for managers and SE for interfacing Partners, because I think that that's something that we can handle really good together. And for the Engineers we need to separate. I think that is what makes most sense for me.

Jomon: So in this engineer's package, are the modules all going to be only at applying level? 

Ulf: No, there could be a hybrid version where you see that there are certain things they all need the same level that are then brought together into one package - "SE for Engineers". And then there can be certain modules that are different for each role cluster. So there could be a hybrid version where you have a common base for all engineers, and then you have a more detailed pathway for each role cluster inside the engineering roles.
For example, for the Engineers where does the differentiation start for modules? The requirements engineer role needs to know more about the requirements management tool. The system architect role needs to know more about the system architecting tool. The verification engineer needs more about verification tools. And so on. 

Jomon: Understood, so the various competencies that are more relevant to those roles, And the tools and methods that go into those competencies. 

If we have modules being repeated across the module packages (SE for Engineers, SE for Managers, ...) they only need to be counted once towards the total number of modules. For example, the module Systems thinking - Understanding level is present across multiple packages, it does not need to be counted multiple times. 

Ulf: where I'm also struggling at is about how do we are able to bring engineers together where they need the same level of competency. For example, like building up the module - understanding in Requirements definition, such that every engineer needs to have that level. But level 4 apply for the Requirements definition - Not all of them needs it. That's why I said we need maybe a primary cluster (SE for engineers) where we can bring them all together. This is where the level of achievement is the same for all the engineers. And then we differentiate again for a certain role clusters or the roles they've defined.

We have the competency data for it. I think we could make a suggestion here, because we have the data for it. We can compare the engineering and see all engineering have here SE for Engineers and we're gonna pick for all engineering roles, every module where they all need the same level. And this is a course then. And then they're gonna be like separations/ pathways for each role where it is necessary or makes sense. I think that is a good good way to detail the subclusters in SE for engineering. 

We've discussed up until here the changes to be made to Role-cluster based view of training program structure.

The Competency level based training program structure is fine as it is now and does not need editing. All we discussed is for the Role-cluster based training program structure.

Now discussing about the "Select Learning Format" feature. In addition to what we've implemented,  I think in Sachin's thesis work, there was also like a short summary description about why each of the 10 learning formats is good for Systems Engineering. Maybe you can just add this sentence alongside the selected learning format description as well. 

Jomon: Understood. It's about why each learning format is suited for SE. 

Ulf: Yes, about the when it is suited for Systems engineering, Sachin has defined some aspects in his thesis and we could use this.

Moving on to phase 4's discussion.

Jomon: Phase 4 is not yet an implemented, and I wanted to check with you regarding Phase 4's design specification. The main two things that we would be generating in phase 4 would be - The RFP - requirement for providers (aka Request for Proposal) document, And the AVIVA dedactics. 

Ulf: Well, I would say actually it's AVIVA as the first step in Phase 4. In the AVIVA topic, we're gonna list the different modules, and for each module we're going to define the A,V,I,V,A steps. Once this is done detailed for all modules, then we can go to the last step which is the export of the RFP document. And this would be then the document where every information that we have gathered and structured in the app (all the 4 phases) is included in this document. This information can maybe be exported in different formats - Word document, Excel sheet, whatever is necessary.

Ulf has also shared with Jomon a sample RFP document ("SE Qualification Program - Input for identifying training service providers.pdf") that he has used in the past for training providers. This sample RFP document does not necessarily contain all the information but is just a reference file to start with. We should also add all the data in the app while creating this RFP document. Jomon will use this as a reference for designing the RFP export feature in phase 4. Ulf has also shared with Jomon a sample AVIVA excel file named "M1+M2 - Konzeption_fein.xlsx". Jomon will use this as a reference for designing the AVIVA export feature in phase 4.

I then showed to Ulf the Phase 3's export Excel feature where it lists all the training modules and their selected formats in an Excel sheet. 

Ulf: so my suggestion for the AVIVA Excel file export file would be now like for each of these modules you have from Phase 3, you will see the AVIVA relevant columns on one side, the columns - Start (time), min (how long it should take), "Type: V= Vortrag, Ü= Übung; P =Pause", AVIVA (which phase of AVIVA is it.), "What" column - what is the Content of the module, then there is "How" column - how is it delivered (keynote, group exercise, one person exercise, etc..), and then there is "Material" column - what material is used (PowerPoint slides, motivation cards, currents, etc..). 
Then, we gotta add a column in the beginning that represents the module (e.g., Systems Thinking - Knowing), then the next columns are the AVIVA columns that I just mentioned. And then the column for what the content is in that module. So, let's think about how we can generate the content for the module. So we could just let this generate by GenAI and say to the user to please adapt it. We could also think about the Content data in H column of the sheet "Learning Objectives" in excel file "Qualifizierungsmodule_Qualifizierungspläne_v4 en-US.xlsx". Here the contents are defined for each of the 16 competencies. These are not detailed content but just some suggestion or idea points to what could be the content. So we could use these points as a baseline and use GenAI to curate and detail it better using GenAI as the content for each of the modules.
Maybe instead of using GenAI for this rightaway, we can give 2 options to the user. The user can either do the detailed planning by themselves and then they can just export a template excelsheet where they detail the "content" column by their own but has all other columns data in it with the Content column as empty, Or the next option to the user that says - Please provide GenAI support in doing this. Now then we can use the Content data from the H column of "Learning Objectives" sheet as a baseline and use GenAI to create the contents alongise the rest of the columns. So these are 2 options that we can provide to the user.

The most important aspect is to always inform the user, and then we can proceed to do with that. For example, informing the user that they can either export the modules sheet without the AVIVA Concept, or, that the system can generate an AVIVA content using GenAI. We should inform the user beforehand What is the content looking like. For example, the content in the Learning Objectives sheet are like "The requirements process in the company", "Life cycle phases", "Operating costs during the life cycle", etc.. (these just need to be listed as bullet points in the frontend UI, so that the user knows what to expect as the contents to be and the user can by themself adapt the exported modules sheet). or if the user chooses the second option to generate an AVIVA content using GenAI automatically.

Ulf: Another thing to add is make the info box more descriptive to the user about the scaled participant estimation in Phase 3. You should maybe just write 2 or 3 more sentence that explains why we are doing the scaled estimation - to ensure that based on the missing numbers, but as a high group of participants for training were selected, we have made these scaled up estimations. Also add this note and info in the exported Excel sheet of Phase 3 as well about the Estimated Participants column that already exists.